{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Vinegar is typically produced in fed batch reactors because", "opta": "a fed batch reactor can be used to maintain low acetic acid concentrations", "optb": "a fed batch reactor can be used to maintain low ethanol concentrations", "optc": "acetic acid bacteria tend to ferment at high ethanol concentrations", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the recovery of citric acid after fermentation, Ca(OH)2 is added to the slurry to", "opta": "precipitate calcium carbonate", "optb": "precipitate calcium citrate", "optc": "precipitate calcium phosphate", "optd": "precipitate calcium sulphate", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following microorganism is used for the production of citric acid?", "opta": "Lactobacillus bulgaricus", "optb": "Saccharomyces cerevisiae", "optc": "Aspergillus niger", "optd": "Streptococcus lactis", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sugar content of the fermentation medium for citric acid is maintained at", "opta": "10-15%", "optb": "15-20%", "optc": "20-25 %", "optd": "25-30 %", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Spirit vinegar is produced from", "opta": "fruit juices", "optb": "malted grain", "optc": "ethanol", "optd": "ale", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the pH of the medium when sucrose is used as substrate for the production of citric acid?", "opta": "3", "optb": "4", "optc": "5", "optd": "6", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In liquid surface culture process for the fermentation to produce citric acid,", "opta": "A. niger is used with solid substrate as sweet potato", "optb": "A. niger floats on the surface of solution", "optc": "Fungal mycelium grows through out the solution in a deep tank", "optd": "both (a) and (b)", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In koji process for the fermentation to produce citric acid,", "opta": "A. niger is used with solid substrate as sweet potato", "optb": "A. niger floats on the surface of solution", "optc": "Fungal mycelium grows through out the solution in a deep tank", "optd": "both (a) and (b)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the pH of the medium when molasses is used as substrate for the production of citric acid?", "opta": "3", "optb": "4", "optc": "5", "optd": "6", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following nitrogen sources is added in the fermentation medium of citric acid production?", "opta": "Ammonium salt", "optb": "Urea", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Peptone", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In submerged process for the fermentation to produce citric acid,", "opta": "A. niger is used with solid substrate as sweet potato", "optb": "A. niger floats on the surface of solution", "optc": "Fungal mycelium grows through out the solution in a deep tank", "optd": "both (a) and (b)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which substrate is used in the fermentation of citric acid?", "opta": "Beet molasses", "optb": "Sucrose", "optc": "Starch hydrolysate", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Alegar is a type of vinegar produced from", "opta": "fruit juices", "optb": "malted grain", "optc": "ethanol", "optd": "ale", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During recovery step of citric acid, calcium citrate formed is treated with which of the following acid to precipitate calcium?", "opta": "HCl", "optb": "HNO3", "optc": "H2SO4", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Vinegar production consists of", "opta": "aerobic fermentation", "optb": "anaerobic fermentation", "optc": "aerobic fermentation followed by anaerobic fermentation", "optd": "anaerobic fermentation followed by aerobic fermentation", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cider vinegar is produced from", "opta": "fruit juices", "optb": "malted grain", "optc": "ethanol", "optd": "ale", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ethanol is oxidized to acetic acid aerobically using", "opta": "Acetobacter", "optb": "Gluconobacter", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Lactobacillus", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Malt vinegar is produced from", "opta": "fruit juices", "optb": "malted grain", "optc": "ethanol", "optd": "ale", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}